<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <newsitem local_id="sumwUpgBsYIRkguTx0OO">
        <language>EN</language>
        <article_size>6x26</article_size>
        <mediatype>print</mediatype>
        <source id="690004" name="The Business Times" country="SG" accesstype="I"/>
        <local_url>6900042025072901010101004.pdf</local_url>
        <original_filename><![CDATA[BT-20250729-BTS-004-00.pdf]]></original_filename>
        <image><![CDATA[]]></image>
        <docdate local="2025-07-29T02:00:00" gmt="2025-07-29T02:00:00" />
        <physical_position page="4" />
        <logical_position value="TOP STORIES" type="section" />
        <headline><![CDATA[BYD tops local car numbers with one-fifth of the market]]></headline>
        <story><![CDATA[ELECTRIC vehicle (EV)-focused China brand BYD has topped new car registrations in Singapore with 4,667 cars in the first half of 2025, Land Transport Authority figures released on Monday (Jul 28) indicated.
This is an 80.4 per cent increase over the 2,587 units the brand registered in H1 2024. BYD increased its market share as it made up 19.5 per cent of the total 23,957 registrations in H1 2025, up from 13.9 per cent in the previous corresponding period.
Mainstream Japanese brand Toyota was in second place with 3,461 registrations, an increase of 9.4 per cent from 3,165 in the previous corresponding period, while its market share grew to 14.4 per cent from 13.9 per cent. BYD is now the clear leader in Singapore's new passenger car market.
In 2024, Toyota registered the most cars with 7,876, compared to BYD's 6,191. But discounting parallel imports, Toyota's authorised distributor sales were 5,736, making it second by that metric.
Total new passenger car registrations for the half were up 29 per cent at 23,957 from 18,576 in H1 2024. German luxury brands BMW and Mercedes-Benz were in third and fourth place, respectively.
BMW upped its numbers to 2,664 from 2,523, while Mercedes-Benz's registrations increased to 2,537 from 2,463, although both brands lost market share.
Fifth-place Japanese mass market brand Honda's registrations rose 50.5 per cent to 2,268. It also increased its market share to 9.5 per cent from 8.1 per cent in the previous corresponding period.]]></story>
<byline name="By Derryn Wong" email="derrynwong@sph.com.sg" />    </newsitem>
</xml>