<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <newsitem local_id="o-mwUpgBsYIRkguTuEOF">
        <language>EN</language>
        <article_size>11x14</article_size>
        <mediatype>print</mediatype>
        <source id="690004" name="The Business Times" country="SG" accesstype="I"/>
        <local_url>6900042025072901010101004.pdf</local_url>
        <original_filename><![CDATA[BT-20250729-BTS-004-00.pdf]]></original_filename>
        <image><![CDATA[]]></image>
        <docdate local="2025-07-29T02:00:00" gmt="2025-07-29T02:00:00" />
        <physical_position page="4" />
        <logical_position value="TOP STORIES" type="section" />
        <headline><![CDATA[COE quota up 3% at 18,701 for August to October]]></headline>
        <story><![CDATA[THEREwillbe18,701Certificatesof Entitlement (COEs) available for tender from August to October 2025.
This is up 3 per cent or 469 COEs from the May to July period, when 18,232 COEs were up for bidding, the Land Transport Authority said on Monday (Jul 28).
The quota for Category A COEs, used to register mainstream passenger cars, will increase by 1 per cent or 75 to 7,586.
Category B COEs, for larger and more powerful cars, will also be up 1 per cent or 48 at 4,737.
Category C, for goods vehicles and buses, will rise 1 per cent or 17 to 1,642 as well.
The quota for Category D, used for motorcycles, will remain unchanged at 3,198.
Meanwhile, the Category E COE supply, which can be used to register any vehicle type except motorcycles, will increase 27.2 per cent to 1,538.
The rise in quota was due to vehicle deregistrations from July 2024 to June 2025, and provisions for 0.25 per cent yearly growth in commercial vehicle (Category C) COEs, based on the category's vehicle population as at Dec 31, 2024.
It also accounted for changes in the taxi population, expired COEs, Early Turnover Scheme for commercial vehicles, redistribution from guaranteed deregistrations for Categories A, B and D, and injection of additional COEs.

Should the COE system for cars borrow ideas from the ABSD regime for homes?, Page 12]]></story>
<byline name="By Tan Nai Lun" email="tnailun@sph.com.sg" />    </newsitem>
</xml>