<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <newsitem local_id="qemwUpgBsYIRkguTu0Ni">
        <language>EN</language>
        <article_size>22x14</article_size>
        <mediatype>print</mediatype>
        <source id="690004" name="The Business Times" country="SG" accesstype="I"/>
        <local_url>6900042025072901010101004.pdf</local_url>
        <original_filename><![CDATA[BT-20250729-BTS-004-00.pdf]]></original_filename>
        <image><![CDATA[EVs are close to displacing petrol-electric hybrids as the most popular type of new passenger vehicle in the city-state.  BLOOMBERG]]></image>
        <docdate local="2025-07-29T02:00:00" gmt="2025-07-29T02:00:00" />
        <physical_position page="4" />
        <logical_position value="TOP STORIES" type="section" />
        <headline><![CDATA[EVs nearly dominant in Singapore, as registrations increase 63% in H1 2025]]></headline>
        <story><![CDATA[ELECTRIC vehicles (EVs) have come close to dominating new passenger car registrations in Singapore in the first six months of 2025, indicated Land Transport Authority figures released on Monday (Jul 28).
The number of EVs registered in the first six months of 2025 increased 63.2 per cent to 9,822, from 6,019 in the previous corresponding period. Petrol-electric hybrid registrations grew 12.6 per cent to 10,045 from 8,922 in the previous corresponding period.
The increase in EVs means they almost displaced petrol-electric hybrids as the dominant type of new passenger vehicle in Singapore for the half-year: 10,045 hybrids make up 41.9 per cent of the total 23,957 registrations for the period, compared with 9,822 EVs representing 41 per cent.
In H1 2024, hybrids made up 48 per cent of registrations, while EVs were 32.4 per cent.
The number of cars powered solely by petrol increased 9.7 per cent to 3,873 in the same period, although their market share dropped to 16.2 per cent from 19 per cent.
Registrations of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles more than doubled to 215 from 96 across the same periods. This comes as total registrations for the first half of the year increased 29 per cent to 23,957.]]></story>
<byline name="By Derryn Wong" email="derrynwong@sph.com.sg" />    </newsitem>
</xml>